🎵Music Playing🎵 🎵Music Playing🎵
这。
是二零二五年福建省初中学业水平考试
英语学科听力部分。
该部分共三节。
注意，回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力考试结束前，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案填涂到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间，请各考场根据试音情况将音量调整到最佳状态。
Hi, John. What's your plan for the coming summer vacation?
I'm not sure.
My parents ask me to study at home, but I'd like to spend it abroad.
Which countries would you like to go to?
I have no idea.
I just want to relax, because I feel tired these days.
What about you, Tina?
I plan to do part -time job.
Then, I will take lesson to learn to the violin.
Sound great! 1.
是因到此。
结束听力考试正式开始，请看听力部分第一节。
第一节听下面五个单句：从各小题所给的三幅图中，选出与所听到的句子
内容相关的选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听完每个句子后，你都有五秒的时。
间作答和阅读下一小题，每个句子读两遍。
Domingo's to school on foot every day.
2. I like playing the airhoo in my free time.
3. Tom began to learn Chinese last year.
4. What a nice kitchen you have!
5. country, it's polite to shake hands when we
五，在我们
在我们
第二节，听下列七段对话，根据你所听到的内容。
选择正确答案，共两节，请听第一节。
听下列四段对话，每段对话后有一个问题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出
最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听完每段对话后，你都有五秒的时间，来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话读两遍。
听第一段对话，完成第六小题。
Betty, the hat is so lovely.
Is it yours or Timmy's?
Neither, it is Kate's.
听第二段对话，完成第七小题。
现在你有五秒的时间来阅读这个小题。
How often do you make a study tour, Grace?
We make a study tour every spring and every autumn.
听第三段对话，完成第八。
小题：现在你有五秒的时间来阅读这个小题。
Shall we go to watch a movie this Saturday afternoon?
Alright! There is one at two o 'clock and one at five o 'clock.
Let's make it two o
I have to get home before six o
Shall we go to watch a movie this Saturday afternoon?
Alright! There is one at two o and one at five o
Let's make it two o I have to get home before six o 'clock.
听第四段对话，完成第九小题
现在你有五秒的时间来阅读这个小题。
Mali, what did you do last weekend?
I stayed at home reading.
I felt relaxed and comfortable.
What about you, Wang Ting?
I went to Yunnan.
It was meaningful.
I listened to the stories of the Red Army.
Mali, what did you do last weekend?
I stayed at home reading.
I felt relaxed and comfortable.
What about you, Wang Ting?
I went to Yunnan.
It was meaningful.
I listened to the stories of the Red Army.
请听第二节。
听下列三段对话，每段对话后有两个问题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出
最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听完每段对话后，你都有五秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和。阅读下一小题
，每段对话读两遍。
听第五段对话，完成第十、十一小题。
现在你有十秒的时间来阅读这两个小题。
Can I help you, madam?
Yes, I'd like to buy a gift for my daughter.
The new year is coming.
The clothes are on sale.
The trousers are 45 yuan, and the skirt is 65 yuan.
How about the shoes?
Sorry, they are not on sale.
They are still 55 yuan.
I see. I'll take the skirt.
Can I help you, madam?
Yes, I'd like to buy a gift for my daughter.
The new year is coming.
The clothes are on sale.
The trousers are 45 yuan, and the skirt is 65 yuan.
How about the shoes?
Sorry, they are not on sale.
They are still 55 yuan.
I see. I'll take the skirt.
听第六段对话，完成第十二、十三小题。
现在你有十秒的时间来阅读这。
两个小题。
I'm home, mom.
Look at these vegetables.
Wow, they look nice.
Are they from the market or the farm?
Well, they are from the vegetable garden in our school.
Do you plant them by yourself?
Right. I plant potatoes, Helen plants tomatoes, and Nancy plants carrots.
We share our vegetables with each other.
Great, Bill. We can make tomato and egg soup tonight.
Um, I don't like it.
Why not make some carrot juice?
Good idea. I'm home, mom.
Look at these vegetables.
Wow, they look nice.
Are they from the market or the farm?
Well, they are from the vegetable garden in our school.
Do you plant them by yourself?
Right. I plant potatoes, Helen plants tomatoes, and Nancy plants carrots.
We share our vegetables with each other.
Great, Bill. We can make tomato and egg soup tonight.
嗯，我
don't like it.
Why not make some carrot juice?
Good idea. What lesson did you take?
听第七段对话，完成第十四、十五小题。
现在你有十秒的时间来阅读这两个小题。
3D printing and paper cutting.
Cool. Did you make anything special with 3D printing?
Yes. I made a model bridge for my mother as a birthday gift.
Good for you.
Hi, Wu Hey, Lucy.
I heard you went to a summer camp.
Can you tell me something about it?
There were different kinds of lessons in the summer camp, such as kite making.
Paper cutting and 3D printing.
What lesson did you take?
3D printing and paper cutting.
Cool. Did you make anything special with 3D printing?
Yes. I made a model bridge for my mother as a birthday gift.
Good for you.
第三节听短文，根据你所听到的短文内容及要求。
有完成以下表格，每空一词，填写在试卷的相应位置。
听短文前，你将有二十秒的时间来阅读表格内容。
听完后将给出二十秒的作答时间。
短文读三遍。
Are you a storybook lover?
Have you thought about designing
We are going to have a book cover design competition.
The works should be handed in before next Monday.
The winners will get a set of popular storybooks signed by the writers as prizes.
Here are some rules you should follow.
Firstly, you can use colored pencils only.
Then, choose no more than four colors and pick one of them to be the main color on
the cover. Lastly, make sure you draw the cover all by yourself.
If you want to join in, please visit our website for more information.
Are you a storybook lover?
Have you thought about designing a new cover for your favorite storybook?
We are going to have a book cover design competition.
The works should be handed in before next Monday.
The winners will get a set of popular storybooks signed by the writers as prizes.
Here are some rules you should follow.
Firstly, you can use colored pencils only.
Then, choose no more than four colors and pick one of them to be the main color on
the cover. Lastly, make sure you draw the cover all by yourself.
If you want to join in, please visit our website for more information.
Are you a storybook lover?
Have you thought about designing a new cover for your favorite storybook?
We are going to have a book cover design competition.
The works should be handed in before next Monday.
The winners will get a set of popular storybooks signed by the writers as prizes.
Here are some rules you should follow.
Firstly, you can use colored pencils only.
Then, choose no more than four colors and pick one of them to be the main color on
the cover. Lastly, make sure you draw the cover all by yourself.
If you want to join in, please visit our website for more information.
听力考试到此结束，请考生将正确答案转写到答题卡上，接着完成试卷上
的其他题。